# Oisin Tohak

# **Fullstack Developer**

HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, REACT, PYTHON

Portfolio: www.oisintohak.com

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/oisintohak/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/oisintohak/</a>

Github: https://github.com/oisintohak

Email: mail@oisintohak.com

I'm an accomplished Fullstack developer with extended experience in education and hospitality. Equally comfortable working independently and within a sprint-based agile team environment. A skilled problem-solver and constant learner, I pride myself on delivering a first-rate user experience with every project.

<u>Backend</u>	<u>Transferable</u>
Durthous	
Python	Problem Solving
Flask	Adaptability
Django	Communication
PostgreSQL	Creativity
	Django

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Tutor Support & Developer** - Code Institute, Remote

JAN 2022 - PRESENT

I currently work as a tutor for Code Institute. My duties include:

- Assist students with queries relating to their projects and general course content
- Develop features for Code Institutes student data system using Python (Django), JavaScript, HTML and CSS.

#### Catering Operator - Govindas, Galway Ireland

2012 - 2021

I was involved in all aspects of running a successful catering business. I was the sole operator of this business for extended periods. Duties included:

- Preparing a selection of Indian vegetarian dishes to serve upwards of 400 customers per day.
- Training new staff to correctly follow the correct procedure and ensure that team members operate efficiently with each other.
- Adhering to health and safety requirements, recording consistent temperature checks and sanitation.

#### Freelance/Self-employed - Drum Teacher

I have been playing drums since 2005 and began giving lessons from my home studio in 2016. Being a teacher has given me many transferable skills and given me a deeper understanding of my own learning process. My duties include:

- Creating lesson plans appropriate for various skill levels and age groups.
- Motivating students to practice with diaries and clear goals.
- Ensuring that students enjoy the lessons while also making consistent progress.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **Diploma in Software Development** - Code Institute (Ireland/Remote)

SEPT 2020 - AUG 2021

This was a fully remote course and it is the only University Credit-Rated bootcamp in Europe. Being on a remote course gave me the skillset to communicate and collaborate effectively within a distributed team and I have participated in 2 student hackathons during this course. It is divided into 4 modules and corresponding projects:

- User Centric Frontend Development:
  - o HTML5 & CSS3
  - o Mobile-first and responsive design.
  - o Project Planning and developing from user stories.
  - User Experience
- Interactive Frontend Development
  - Javascript (ES6 & jQuery)
  - o Interacting with APIs
  - Responding to user input
- Data Centric Development
  - Python
  - Flask Framework
  - SQL
  - o MongoDB
- Full Stack Frameworks
  - Django Framework
  - PostgreSQL
  - Ecommerce Development & Payment Processing